Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Annotated Scores, 1828-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Additional annotated scores received 2016, 1916-1994, VIII.; Folder 1219-1337
  - Raphael, Günter, 1903-1960 Kleine sonate, op. 2, 1924, 1 score (21 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Raphael to unknown recipient, dated 1924. Publisher: Breitkopf & Härtel (Box 55, Folder 1300)
  - Raskatov, A. (Aleksandr) Consolation, 1989, 1 score (22 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Includes several blue pen and pencil markings. (Box 55, Folder 1301)
  - Rea, John, 1944- Meninas, 1991, 1 score (52 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Rea to Mikhashoff on title page. Publisher: Musigraphe Èditions (Box 55, Folder 1302)
  - Rodrigo, Joaquín Ombre de "Torre Bermeja", 1947, 1 score (9 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Rodrigo to Mikhashoff in caption. Publisher: Joaquin Rodrigo (Box 55, Folder 1303)
  - Samuel, Virginia Impromptu, 1991, 1 score (15 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Signed by Samuel. (Box 55, Folder 1304)
  - Scolari, Henri, 1923- Eoliennes, 1975, 1 score (26 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Includes small number of performance markings. (Box 55, Folder 1305)
  - Sellars, James, 1943-2017 Amor brujo, 1979, 1 score (5 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Sellars to Mikhashoff on title page. Text by Harold Norse. (Box 55, Folder 1306)
  - Sellars, James, 1943-2017 Separate ways, 1978, 1 score (25 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For violoncello and piano Inscription from Sellars to Mikhashoff on title page. Includes many blue pen, red pen, and pencil performance markings. "For Frances Marie-Uitti and Yvar Mikhashoff". (Box 55, Folder 1307)
  - Shim, Kunsu Konzentration, 1984, 1 score (7 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Shim to Mikhashoff on title page. (Box 55, Folder 1308)
  - Shim, Kunsu Tendenz, 1985, 1 score (9 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For oboe, violin, and piano Inscription from Shim to Mikhashoff on prefatory page. (Box 55, Folder 1309)
  - Shohl, David Dynamophone, 1989, 1 score (11 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Shohl to Mikhashoff on cover, dated 1990. (Box 55, Folder 1310)
  - Slettholm, Yngve, 1955- Magma, 1980, 1 score (13 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Slettholm to Mikhashoff on cover verso, dated 1984. Publisher: Harald Lyche and Co. A. S. Musikkforlag (Box 55, Folder 1311)
  - Slonimsky, Nicholas, 1894-1995 Anti-Dodecaphonic declaration, 1989, 1 score (1 page); Holograph For two voices or alternating violins and piano Signed by Sloninsky. Includes dynamic and expression markings in pen from composer. (Box 55, Folder 1312)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Mountain eulogy, 1975, 1 score (29 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For speaker and piano Inscription from Smit to Mikhashoff on title page. "Commissioned by the Studio Arena Theatre for Paul Schmidt and Yvar Mikhashoff in memory of Vera Brynner". From Peer Gynt by Henrik Ibsen. (Box 55, Folder 1313)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sonata in one movement, 1967, 1 score(19 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Smit to Mikhashoff on title page, dated 1976. Publisher: Mills Music (Box 55, Folder 1314)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Transient view, 1976, 1 score (11 pages); Print For mixed voices (unison, two, three and four equal parts) a cappella Inscription from Smit to Mikhashoff: in caption. Publisher: Carl Fischer On texts by Katie Louchheim. (Box 55, Folder 1315)
  - Smith, Stuart, 1948- Pinetop, 1981, 1 score (8 pages); Print (Reproduction of manuscript) For solo piano Inscription from Smith to Mikhashoff on cover. Publisher: Lingua Press (Box 55, Folder 1316)
  - Stäbler, Gerhard Traum 1/9/92 - Klavier, 1992, 1 score (15 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Stabler to Mikhashoff on cover, dated 1993. Includes several red pen markings. Publisher: Ricordi (Box 55, Folder 1317)
  - Terzian, Barbara A. Toccata, 1955, 1 score (11 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Terzian to Mikhashoff on title page. Publisher: Ricordi Americana (Box 55, Folder 1318)
  - Theobald, James C. (James Chester), 1950- Three places in New York, 1975, 1 score (16 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid reproduction) For solo piano Inscription from James A. Theobald to Mikhashoff on wrapper. Folder includes newspaper article about the composer. (Box 55, Folder 1319)
    Contents: Harlem -- Red Hook --Brownsville - East New York (Variations of "We Shall Overcome").
  - Thomas, John Patrick 145 West 85th Street, 1971, 1 score (17 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Thomas to Mikhashoff on title page. (Box 55, Folder 1320)
  - Tzeng, Shing-Kwei Variations, undated, 1 score (15 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Tzeng to Mikhashoff in caption. Includes a biography and works list of the composer. (Box 56, Folder 1321)
  - Ulehla, Ludmila, 1923-2009 Harlequinade, undated, 1 score (9 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid reproduction) For solo piano Inscription from Ulehla to Mikhashoff in caption. (Box 56, Folder 1322)
  - Vigeland, Nils Brinks!, 1982, 2 scores (12 pages, 10 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For violoncello and piano Includes several pencil performance markings and white-out corrections. For Jan Williams and Yvar Mikhashoff. (Box 56, Folder 1323)
  - Vigeland, Nils London nocturne, 1985, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph For solo piano Includes several white-out corrections. For Yvar Mikhashoff. (Box 56, Folder 1324)
  - Vigeland, Nils Piano sonata, 1979, 1 score (28 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid reproduction) For solo piano Inscription from Vigeland to Mikhashoff on title page. Includes several pencil performance markings and white-out corrections. (Box 56, Folder 1325)
  - Vigeland, Nils Second piano sonata, undated, 1 score (5 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Signed by Vigeland. For Yvar Mikhashoff. (Box 56, Folder 1326)
    Contents: Probably incomplete.
  - Viinholt Nielsen, Bendt Little waltz: tired of tangoes!, 1986, 1 score (2 pages); Holograph For solo piano Inscription from Viinholt Nielsen to Mikhashoff on verso of page 1, dated 1986. (Box 56, Folder 1327)
  - Villeneuve, André W. Troisième terre - sonitor, 1991, 1 score (12 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Villeneuve to Mikhashoff on title page. Includes several pencil performance markings. (Box 56, Folder 1328)
  - Ware, Peter, 1951- Piscataway: 'on looking deeper into the water', 1979, 1 score (15 pages); Manuscript (Photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Ware to Mikhashoff on title page verso. Includes several pencil performance markings. Includes two errata pages. Revised 1982. "Composed for Yvar Mikhashoff, Adam Felligi". "Dedicated to Yvar Mikhashoff, Adam Fellegi, Gary Smart, Naomi Oliphant, Alison Ball". (Box 56, Folder 1329)
  - Ware, Peter, 1951- Piscataway I: 'on looking deeper into the water', 1982, 1 score (15 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from Ware to Mikhashoff on dedication page. Publisher: Acoma Composer's Edition "Composed for Yvar Mikhashoff, Adam Felligi". "Dedicated to Yvar Mikhashoff, Adam Fellegi, Gary Smart, Naomi Oliphant, Alison Ball". (Box 56, Folder 1330)
  - Ware, Peter, 1951- Piscataway II: 'the hibiscus on the water', 1980, 1 score (5 pages); Manuscript (Photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Ware to Mikhashoff on title page. Includes several performance markings. "Composed for: Yvar Mikhashoff, Adam Felligi". "Dedicated to: Deborah Dunning, Yvar Mikhashoff, Adam Felligi, Scott Huston, Florence Robertson". (Box 56, Folder 1331)
  - Weiner-Dillmann, Hans Je t'aime: kleines französisches Walzerrondo, 1982, 1 score (2 pages); Print For solo piano Inscription from "Hanna" (unknown) to Mikhashoff on cover. Publisher: Edition Standart (Box 56, Folder 1332)
  - Weinzweig, John, 1913- 3 pieces for piano, 1989, 1 score (18 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Weinzweig to Mikhashoff on title page, dated 1990. (Box 56, Folder 1333)
    Contents: Pentad -- Aeolian -- Élan.
  - Wiéner, Jean 3 moments de musique, 1980, 1 score (21 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Inscription from Wiéner to Mikhashoff on cover. (Box 56, Folder 1334)
  - Willey, James, 1939- Prayer after all!, 1980, 2 scores (24 pages each); Manuscript (Ozalid reproduction) For solo piano A letter from Willey to Mikhashoff attached. Includes several pencil performance markings. Includes poem by John Berryman. (Box 56, Folder 1335)
  - Winkler, Stephan, 1967- Tasten, 1990, 1 score (1 page); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano Includes a letter from Winkler to Mikhashoff. Includes an analysis by the composer. "Dedicated to Yvar Mikhashoff.". (Box 56, Folder 1336)
  - Yannay, Yehuda, 1937- Seven late spring pieces, 1981, 1 score (15 pages); Print For solo piano Includes a letter from Yannay to Mikhashoff and an inscription from Yannay to Mikhashoff dated 1981. Publisher: Israel Music Institute (Box 56, Folder 1337)
- Additional unmarked scores received 2016, 1964-1988, IX.; Folder 1338-1353
  This series contains scores without substantive markings.
  - Baltin, A. (Aleksandr) Dve p'esy, 1969, 2 scores (19 and 8 pages); Print For piano and violin Publisher: Vsesoyuznoye Izdatel'stvo First score is a complete score, with piano and violin music. Second score is violin part only. (Box 57, Folder 1338)
    Contents: Melodija -- Skerco.
  - Belimov, S. (Sergeĭ) Sonata una corda, undated, 1 score (8 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano (Box 57, Folder 1339)
  - Greenberg, Alexander Polyphonic games, 1 score (77 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) For solo piano (Box 57, Folder 1340)
    Contents: Preludio -- Canone per inversio -- Ciaccona -- Recitativi -- Fuga -- Inventio -- Canone d'altezza -- Passacaglia -- Canone di misura -- Poco tranquillo -- Chorale -- Ricercar per tre teme.
  - Knaĭfelʹ, Aleksandr Aronovich Klassicheskaya syuita, 1976, 1 score (11 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Vsesoyuznoye Izdatel'stvo Sovetskiy Kompozitor (Box 57, Folder 1341)
  - Knaĭfelʹ, Aleksandr Aronovich Musique militaire, 1964, 1 score (14 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Izdatel'stvo muzyka (Box 57, Folder 1342)
  - Knaĭfelʹ, Aleksandr Aronovich Spor istin, 1976, 1 score (2 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Izdatel'stvo muzyka (Box 57, Folder 1343)
  - Rääts, Jaan, 1932- Sonaat No. 5, 1980, 1 score (19 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Muzyka Moscow (Box 57, Folder 1344)
  - Rääts, Jaan, 1932- Toccata, 1977, 1 score (14 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Associated Music Publishers (Box 57, Folder 1345)
  - Rakov, Nikolai Petrovich, 1908- Sonata in the classical style, 1965, 1 score (20 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Muzyka Moscow (Box 57, Folder 1346)
  - Shchedrin, Rodion Konstantinovich, 1932- Sonata, 1976, 1 score (33 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: G. Schirmer (Box 57, Folder 1347)
  - Smirnov, Dmitrii (Dmitrii Nikolaevich) Seven angels of William Blake, 1988, 1 score (33 pages); Print For solo piano (Box 57, Folder 1348)
    Contents: Prelude -- Lucifer, the Morning Star -- Molech, the Executioner -- Elohim creating Adam, Adam creating Elohim -- Shaddai's Anger -- Pachad's Fear -- Jehovah appealing to Eternity -- Jesus the Lamb.
  - Smirnov, Dmitrii (Dmitrii Nikolaevich) Sonata no. 2, 1983, 1 score (13 pages); Print (photocopy) For solo piano Publisher: Boosey and Hawkes Music Archives (Box 57, Folder 1349)
  - Kontsertnye proizvedeniya sovetskikh kompozitorov = Concert pieces by Soviet composers, 11, 13, 1984, 1985, 2 scores (79 pages and 120 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Vsesoyuznoye Izdatel'stvo Sovetskiy Kompozitor Contains a number of works by Society composers. (Box 57, Folder 1350-1351)
  - Large-scale compositions of young Muscovites for piano = Molodye kompozitory Moskvy proizvedeniya krupnoi formy dlya fortepiano, 1985, 1 score (78 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Moscow "Muzyka" (Box 57, Folder 1352)
    Contents: Fantazii︠a︡ do minor pami︠a︡ti M.V. I︠U︡dinoĭ: op. 21 (1983) / V. Ri︠a︡bov -- Sonata, kompozit︠s︡ii︠a︡ 33 (1981) / V. Ekimovskiĭ -- Sonata no. 2 (1980) / V. Lobanov -- Sonata no. 2: fantasia quasi una sonata: 1981 / S. Pavlenko.
  - Piesi za piano ot bulgarski kompozitori, 1988, 1 score (67 pages); Print For solo piano Publisher: Izdatelstvo muzkya (Box 57, Folder 1353)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music; Music--Manuscripts; Piano music
Genres
Scores
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Archive
The Yvar Mikhashoff Archive consists of the following separate components. Descriptions can be found at the page for the Yvar Mikhashoff Archive at
http://library.buffalo.edu/music/special-materials/yvar-mikhashoff/
:
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Compositions
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Transcriptions
Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Tangos
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Sound Recordings
Yvar Mikhashoff Cassette Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Video Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Slide Collection